ISURI DEVINDI

Department of Computer Engineering, University of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka





My primary research interest lies in developing low-energy, context-aware Human-Al collaborative systems using deep learning and computer vision for real-time, adaptive interactions in healthcare and everyday environments.

EDUCATION

BSc.Eng (Hons.) in Computer Engineering

University of Peradeniya 2018 Nov - 2023 Dec

G.C.E. Advanced Level Examination

Hillwood College, Kandy

2004 - 2017

First Class Hons.

Class rank: 1/415

GPA: 4.00/4.00

Z-Score: 2.2768 District rank: 6/2784

National Rank: 113 / 32075

PUBLICATIONS

[J 3] IEEE Access

Multimodal Deep Convolutional Neural Network Pipeline for Al-Assisted Early Detection of Oral Cancer



Isuri Devindi, Dinura Dissanayake, Sashini Liyanage, Achintha Harshamal, Dhanushki Mapitigama, Nadisha Piyarathne, Kalani Hettiarachchi, Sumudu Rasnayaka, Ruwan Jayasinghe, Roshan Ragel, Isuru Nawinne

Contribution: Conceptualization, Methodology, Software, Validation, Writing - Original Draft. Review & Editing

[J 2] Nature Scientific Reports

A Novel ECG Compression Algorithm Using PWM-Integrated Quantization for Low-Power Real-Time Monitoring



Isuri Devindi, Sashini Liyanage, Titus Jayarathna, Janaka Alawatugoda, Roshan Ragel Contribution: Conceptualization, Methodology, Software, Validation, Writing - Original Draft, Review & Editing

Oral Oncology

[J 1] Science Direct Comprehensive Dataset of Annotated White Light Images of Oral Cavity and Novel Web Tool for Image Annotation



N. S. Piyarathne, S.N. Liyanage, R.M.S.G.K. Rasnayaka, P.V.K.S. Hettiarachchi, G.A.I. Devindi, F.B.A.H. Francis, D.M.D.R. Dissanayake, R.A.N.S. Ranasinghe, M.B.D. Pavithya, I. Nawinne, R.G. Ragel, R.D. Jayasinghe

Contribution: Software, Data curation

[C 1] IEEE: Moratuwa Engineering Research Conference 2024

EEG Based Brain-Computer Interface for Inner Speech Classification

Praveen Dhananjaya, Isurika Adikari, Sumudu Lakmali, Isuri Devindi, Sashini Liyanage, Mahanama Wickramasingha, Theekshana Dissanayake, Roshan G. Ragel, Isuru Nawinne

Contribution: Writing - Review & Editing, Visualization



[C 2] IEEE: Moratuwa Engineering Research Conference 2024

Self-Paced Brain-Computer Interface on Sensorimotor Rhythms for **Controlling Virtual Objects**

A.D. Athapattu, P.S.B. Dassanayake, G.S.C. Nanayakkara, S.N. Liyanage, G.A.I. **Devindi**, Roshan G. Ragel, Theekshana Dissanayake, Isuru Nawinne

Contribution: Writing - Review & Editing, Visualization



[C 3] IEEE: Moratuwa Engineering Research Conference 2024

Decoding Non-Motor Imagery Tasks with Non-Invasive EEG Based **Brain Computer Interface: A Review**

Sumudu Lakmali, Praveen Dhananjaya, Isurika Adikari, Isuri Devindi, Sashini Liyanage, Mahanama Wickramasingha, Theekshana Dissanayake, Roshan G. Ragel, Isuru Nawinne Contribution: Writing - Review & Editing



EXPERIENCE

Instructor 2024 Jan

- Present Department of Computer Engineering, University of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka

> Teaching, conducting lab sessions, preparing tutorials, lab specification sheets for courses; Computer Architecture (CO224), Image Processing (CO543), Operating Systems

(CO327), Python Programming (CO1010)

2023 Jan Visiting Research Assistant Supervised by Prof. Archan Misra

- 2023 May Pervasive Sensing & Systems Lab, Singapore Management University

> Exploring spatiotemporal compressive sensing techniques for event-based neuromorphic vision sensor data fed into and processed by Spiking Neural Networks (View project details).

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant 2021 - 2022

> Department of Computer Engineering, University of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka Supervising and assisting in weekly lab sessions for courses; Embedded Systems (CO321), Data Structures and Algorithms (CO322), Programming and Networking (CO253), Pro-

gramming Methodology (C language) (CO222)

Technical Article Writer (Part-time) 2021 - Present

Enlear Pvt. Ltd

Writing technical content on computer vision, machine learning, and web development.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Best Paper Award in Biomedical Engineering Track at MERCon 2024 2024

> Received the Best Paper Award for the paper EEG Based Brain-Computer Interface for Inner Speech Classification in the Biomedical Engineering track at the Moratuwa Engineering Research Conference (MERCon) 2024.

Gold Medal for Excellence in Computer Engineering 2024

> Awarded to the student with the highest GPA in the branch of Computer Engineering at the BSc Engineering Programme at the University of Peradeniya (Out of 60)

Award for Engineering Mathematics 2024

> Prof. T.D.M.A. Samuel prize awarded for the student with the highest GPA for a minimum of nineteen credits of Engineering Mathematics courses at the University of Peradeniya (Out of 415 students)

Award for Best Industrial Trainee in Computer Engineering in Sri Lanka 2024

> Awarded to top final-year engineering undergraduates in Sri Lanka (out of all state universities), based on their performance in 20-week industrial training, evaluated by the Institution of Engineers, Sri Lanka (IESL)

Bronze Award in NBQSA 2023 | National ICT Awards 2023

> Bronze award in Tertiary Student Projects (Technology) (Out of 46 teams) for the project "Oral Cavity Image Annotation and Cancer Prediction from White Light Images"

IEEEXtreme 16.0 | 24 hour global algorithmic programming competition 2022

Team Name - bitLasagna, Country Rank - 27, Global Rank - 427

(Out of 14600+ participants)

ACES Coders V9.0 | 12 hour national algorithmic programming competition

The biggest annual on-ground inter-university 12-hour coding competition in Sri Lanka organized by the University of Peradeniya.

Team Name – Zblunt, Country Rank – 6 (Out of 100+ teams)

OTHER PROJECTS

2023 Jan - Efficient Event Stream Compression for Low-Energy Neuromorphic Systems | Individual

Under the supervision of <u>Prof. Archan Misra</u>, explored compressive sensing techniques (rate coding, latency coding, delta modulation, event and time window slicing, voxel cubes) to convert event-based neuromorphic vision sensor data into 2D frames for low-energy spiking neural networks (SNNs) and evaluated their impact on classification and object detection performance.

Technology: snnTorch, PyTorch, Python

2022 Jan - Reconstructing Highly Degraded License Plates | Group

Demonstrated the efficacy of traditional image processing techniques to reconstruct highly degraded license plate images from CCTV footage with unknown degradation sources.

Contribution: Explored methods such as Otsu thresholding, morphological transformations, con-

Contribution: Explored methods such as Otsu thresholding, morphological transformations, contouring, spatial and frequency domain filtering, and Wiener filter-based degradation modeling for reconstruction.

Technology: Python, OpenCV

2021 Remote Proctoring System | Group

A single device with video streaming facility that integrates the hardware and software components needed to conduct virtual proctoring of an examination in a university.

Contribution: Designed a scalable web application for administrators and proctors, and developed the hardware solution using a Raspberry Pi.

Technology: React.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Node.js

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES & LEADERSHIPS HELD

2020 - 2024 Member of the Web Consultation team of University of Peradeniya

Group focused on improving university's digital presence

2023 Committee member of the Association of Computer Engineering Students

(ACES) of the University of Peradeniya

Contributed to the team that designed algorithmic programming questions for the ACES

Coders v10.0 competition.

2022 - 2023 Secretary of IET on Campus of the University of Peradeniya

2021 - 2022 President of the Music Society of the University of Peradeniya

2022 - Present Compère Speaker at various events at the University of Peradeniya

REFERENCES

Prof. Roshan G. Ragel | roshanr@eng.pdn.ac.lk

Head of Department, Department of Computer Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, University of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka **Dr. Isuru Nawinne** | isurunawinne@eng.pdn.ac.lk

Senior Lecturer, Department of Computer Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, University of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka Prof. Archan Misra | archanm@smu.edu.sg

Vice Provost (Research), School of Computing & Information Systems, Singapore Management University, Singapore